Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Markle.
My name is Catherine
and today we've got a
lesson for you that's
about an unusual topic.
Something we've never talked
about here on EnglishPod.
That's right. As you know in EnglishPod
we like to talk about all sorts of topics,
especially topics that
are real-life topics.
So probably a lot of
things that you won't find
in your normal English notebooks
or English learning books.
That's right. So we want to tell you in
advance today's lesson is about drugs.
So if you're a younger user or you have, if
you have kids, maybe they shouldn't listen
to today's lesson. But you're going to
learn a lot of the names for drugs and also
how to turn down and offer of drugs. So
let's check out today's dialogue and we've
back in a moment to talk about
the things that you've heard.
Hey man, you want to buy some weed?
Some what? Weed, you know,
pot, gonga, merry jane, some chronic.
Oh, no thanks. I also have blow
if you prefer to do a few blinds.
No, I'm okay. Really. Come on man.
I've even got dope and acid. Try some.
Do you really have all of these drugs?
Where do you get them from?
I got my connections.
Just tell me what you
want and I'll even give
you an ounce for free.
Hmm, sounds good. Let's
see. I want. Yeah? I want you
to put your hands behind
your head. You're under arrest.
Don't!
All right, we're
back. So as Catherine
mentioned, obviously,
everywhere in the world,
maybe most likely
you've been off for drugs.
So we're not only going
to talk about drugs,
but we're also going to give you some vocab
in English how to reject or turn down the
offer of drugs. And now what we're going
to take a look at, let's start in language
takeaway with some of the
names of these drugs in English.
Language takeaway. Okay, so
we're in language takeaway here.
And I want to warn you,
some of these words are slang. That means
they're not words from like a dictionary.
These are words people use
when they're talking to each
other in daily life or words
that you hear on the street.
That's right. You may even
hear them a lot in movies as well.
Movies and TV. So
this first one, weed is
something, there's even
a TV show called weeds.
That's right. That
talks about this topic.
So weed is the street name or the most
common name for the drug marijuana.
That's right. marijuana
is the drug name.
But there are many,
many, many other names in
English that you'll hear. So weed is one of
them. A weed is a kind of thing that grows
like grass or a flower that you cut because
you don't want it. It's bad. It smells bad.
That's right. That's exactly right. So the
the colloquial name for marijuana is weed.
And obviously the
person that's being offered
these drugs doesn't
understand what that means.
So he goes on and
he gives a couple
of different other street
names for the same drug.
So the first one. So
the next one is pot.
That's right. So he says
pot or ganga or Mary Jane
or even chronic. So all of these are
synonyms. They mean exactly the same thing.
They all mean marijuana.
Okay. But then after
that, the drug dealer
offers other kinds
of drugs. He says blow.
So now we may know
the verb to blow. Right.
That's right to blow air.
But in this case,
it's a noun. Okay.
So he says, I have
blow. That's right.
So he's offering this drug
called blow. And what is blow?
Blow is the street
name for cocaine.
So there's a very famous
movie called blow. And it
was about selling cocaine. Now. So after he
talks about having blow, he also says, if
you want to do a few
lines. And so this is
what you'll commonly hear,
people saying how they do this drug.
That's right. So for
example, you may know
that many drugs, they're
consumed in different ways.
For example, weed,
people smoke it.
Right. In this case,
when we're talking about
cocaine or blow, then
that's why he refers
to do a few lines. All
right. Because people
breathe it in through
their nose. That's right.
So that's the colloquial
way of saying of
how you say that how
you consume this drug.
Okay. So moving along,
there's two more drugs
that got mentioned
in today's dialogue.
They're dope and acid.
Now dope can mean two
different things. Sometimes
it means marijuana.
Like some of those other
words we heard earlier.
But sometimes it also means a very, very
serious drug called crack cocaine. Okay.
And that's something that people
breathe in. And it's very, very addictive.
Yeah. That's right. And also the other word
that we have there, or the other drug acid,
you may know the word acid
is a very harmful substance.
Like for example, batteries, they
have a certain type of acid that, for
example, will melt
metal. Or if it gets on your
skin, it will burn you. That's right.
But acid, when it's a drug, means LSD.
And that is a drug that people
take that makes them see things.
So it's called a hallucinogenic.
It makes you see crazy
things. And it was very,
very popular in the
1970s. That's right.
So that's acid or
LSD. Very good.
So we've taken a look at a lot of
vocab here specifically all the drugs.
Why don't we go back to our
dialogue? Let's take another listen and
we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
Now, I'm okay.
Really. Come on, man.
I've even got dope and
acid. Try some. Do you really
have all of these drugs? What do you get
them from? I got my connections. Just tell
me what you want. And I'll even give
you an ounce for free. Hmm. Sounds good.
Let's see. I want. Yeah.
I want you to put your
hands behind your
head. You're under arrest.
Don't!
Okay. So now in fluency builder, we've got
a couple of phrases for you about the other
side of things. How
to say no to drugs and
what you might hear
from a police officer like
we hear in today's
dialogue. That's right.
So let's take a look at
these phrases in fluency
builder. Fluency builder. So the first one
we hear is no thanks. So the guy says, um,
no thanks. He
doesn't want the drugs.
That's right. So obviously
you're being offered
something that you
don't like. Let's take into
consideration drugs or
maybe somebody wants
to offer you a drink or somebody wants to
take you on a date. You can say no thanks.
No thanks. So hey, Marco, uh, you want to
drink? I'm going to go right now. It's only
like two o'clock, but you
know, we could go for a drink.
No thanks. No. Okay. Right.
And now we also
have another phrase.
If a person insists, the
person is continually insisting,
like, come on, come on, Marco, let's go for
a drink. I really want a drink. Come with
me. Right. And I, and you can say, no,
I'm okay really. So it may sound confusing.
I am okay, because that would
mean you're in good health.
I feel good. I feel good.
But I am, in this case, when
you say to someone, no, I'm okay.
You're saying, no,
I'm fine the way I am.
I don't, I don't really
need to do anything.
I don't need it. So I'm
okay means I don't need it.
All right. And this is a great way to,
to really say, listen, no, I don't want
it. Okay. So those are
the two ways that we have
in, in which you can say
no, we're going to give
you a couple of more
towards the end of the lesson.
But let's take a look very
quickly at our next phrase.
When the police officer
said, you are under arrest.
All right. So the man didn't know, the
person didn't know this was a police officer.
And finally in the end, he
says, you are under arrest.
That's right. Okay. So this is something
you hear in the movies when they put the
hand cuffs on somebody.
The, the preposition is under.
It's strange, but you just have to remember
this as a phrase. You are under arrest.
I am arresting you. That
means you are going to the
police station with me.
You broke the law. Right.
Or you can say, Oh,
Tim is under arrest.
He's at the police station
right now. Okay. All right.
So we've taken a look at
a couple of phrases and a
couple of different
things. Why don't we take
another short break.
Let's listen to our dialogue
and we'll be back
in a bit. Hey, man.
You want to buy some weed?
Some what weed? You know,
pot, Ganga, Mary
Jane, some chronic.
Oh, no, thanks. I also have
below if you prefer to do a few
lines. No, I'm okay.
Really. Come on, man.
I even got dope and acid.
Try some. Do you really have
all of these drugs? What
do you get them from?
I got my connections.
Just tell me what you want
and I'll even give you
a noun for free. Hmm.
Sounds good. Let's see. I
want. Yeah. I want you to put
your hands behind your
head. You are under arrest.
All right. So obviously
a very serious topic,
but at the same time,
I think very necessary
because it may happen or
you may hear it in a movie.
And it's part of the
English language.
Now, obviously, we are not
advocating or saying that drugs
are good or anything.
We are saying we are
giving you the tools so
you know how to recognize
when somebody is
offering you a drug and the
way that you can say
no. That's right. So,
remember that these
are things that you might
hear when you're in a
country like America or
England or Australia.
We hope that you don't
have to worry about
this. But if you do hear it,
or you hear it in a
movie, you will understand
it. But more, we had
some other ways to say no
to drugs, right, to say no
to something, to refuse.
So we heard no
thanks. And I'm okay.
But what are some
other ways to say no?
Well, for example, if the
person also persists or insists,
you can say no, I'm
good. Thank you. I'm good.
Yeah. So it doesn't
really make sense because
you're saying I'm good.
What does that exactly mean?
So like Marco, you
want to cigarette?
No, I'm good. Thanks.
Okay. So that's a way of
saying no thanks. No,
thanks. Also, I'm cool.
Not saying like, I'm
really cool. Right.
It's like saying no, I'm
good. I'm cool. Thanks.
That's right. I'm cool.
Thank you. No, thank you.
Or as well, you can also
just say no, thank you.
I think the most clear is no, I don't smoke
or no, I don't do drugs. Yes. Exactly.
That's the, that's the verb that
we use when referring to drugs.
You do drugs.
You don't do drugs.
So he does drugs or don't do
drugs. You often hear this phrase.
So you can say, listen,
no, no, thank you.
I'm cool. I don't do
drugs. That's right.
So as we said, this is all
the kind of street slang
or colloquial, very
common ways of referring to
drugs in, in English. So you
can keep an eye out for that.
If you hear that in movies, now, you know,
more or less what they're referring to.
And also, of course, if
you have any questions,
any comments or any
suggestions, we are always
available on our
website, englishpot.com.
We hope to see you guys
there. And until next time, bye.
[Music]